"The Healthiest Way to Drink Coffee"
As I explained
in my last video,
chlorogenic acid,
the main antioxidant in coffee,
enhances autophagy
in human cells,
which may explain why coffee
is linked to a longer life.
If everyone drank three cups
(720 ml) of coffee a day,
millions of healthy
years of life
could potentially be saved
every year
in the United States alone.
Which coffee has
the most chlorogenic acid?
More than a hundred coffees,
espressos, cappuccinos,
and instant coffees
have been tested,
and chlorogenic acid contents
varied by more than 30-fold.
Interestingly, the major
contributor to this wide range
was the coffee
purchased from Starbucks,
which had an extremely low
antioxidant content.
This may be because Starbucks
roasts its beans so dark,
it destroys it.
The more you roast coffee,
the lower
the antioxidant levels fall.
Caffeine is relatively stable
to heat,
but a dark roast may wipe out
nearly 90 percent
of the chlorogenic acid content
of the beans.
However, the difference
between a medium-light roast
and a medium roast
did not appear to matter,
at least when it came
to boosting
the total antioxidant status
in people's bloodstream
after drinking them.
Soy milk in coffee
appears to be fine,
but adding dairy milk
or creamer
seems to cut
the bioavailability
of chlorogenic acid
down by about 40 percent.
The freeze-drying
and spray-drying processes
used to make instant coffee
don't appear
to significantly affect
chlorogenic acid levels,
but the method of preparing
fresh coffee does.
Brewed coffee has higher
chlorogenic acid content
than espresso,
presumably due
to the longer contact time
between the water
and coffee grounds
and the greater
ultimate volume.
No differences were found
between cold brew or hot.
The brewing method
can also impact
our cholesterol levels.
The culprits are two compounds,
cafestol and kahweol,
which are found in the fines
of the coffee grounds,
tiny particles that get trapped
in the paper filter,
which explains
why filtered coffee
doesn't raise cholesterol
as much as boiled,
French press,
or Turkish coffee does.
If you don't have
optimal cholesterol levels,
you should consider sticking
to paper-filtered coffee
or using instant coffee
which also lacks
these compounds.
Mesh filters are
likely insufficient,
as even paper filters
sporting "micro perforations"
allow more of the
cholesterol-raising compounds
to slip through,
particularly when the coffee
is ground especially fine.
And indeed,
those drinking unfiltered coffee
were found to have
higher mortality rates
than those drinking
filtered coffee,
though any kind of coffee
may be better
than no coffee at all,
at least for women.
These findings
led some to bemoan
the growing popularity
of unfiltered brews
from capsule coffee machines,
but if you cut them open,
you can see
the little plastic cups
actually do have
a paper filter inside.
However, capsule coffee
ends up with more estrogenic
chemicals in it,
as one would expect
from exposing
nearly any sort of plastic
to hot enough water,
but the levels were found low
compared to established
safety guidelines.
If coffee can extend our lives
by boosting autophagy,
potentially preventing
hundreds of thousands
of cases or deaths
from various diseases,
should everyone be drinking it?
Is there anyone
who should avoid coffee?
We'll find out next.